舰长日志，星历2947.3
Captain's log, stardate 2947.3.
我们遭遇了一场巨大的离子风暴
We have been through a severe ion storm.
一名船员不幸牺牲
One crewman is dead.
舰体严重损坏
Ship's damage is considerable.
我下令飞船临时停靠在11号星际基地进行维修
I have ordered a nonscheduled layover on Starbase 11 for repairs.
有关舰体的详细损坏报告已递交给
A full report of damages was made to the commanding officer
11号星际基地指挥官，斯通准将
of starbase 11, Commodore stone.
18号维修点
Maintenance Section 18.
你们当前的工作是在为无畏号进行维修
Your section is working on the Intrepid.
我重新安排你们优先维修进取号
Reschedule. The Enterprise is on priority one.
你已经读了3遍了，吉姆
That makes three times you've read it, Jim.
- 有什么问题吗？ - 没有
- Is there an error? - No.
- 但有船员牺牲了 - 这并不罕见，舰长
- But the death of a crewman-- - Regulations, captain.
你船上的计算机记录能为你提供证词吗？
The extracts from your ship's computer log confirming this sworn deposition?
- 寇克呼叫进取号 - 舰桥收到，请说，舰长
- Kirk to Enterprise. - Bridge here. Go ahead, captain.
史波克和计算机记录的数据在哪？
Where's Mr. Spock with that computer log extract?
他10分钟前应该就在那里了，长官
Well, he should've been there ten minutes ago, sir.
- 寇克，完毕 - 很遗憾
- Kirk, out. - It's a great pity.
军队无法失去像芬尼少校这样的人
The service can't afford to lose men like Lieutenant Commander Finney.
我了解，但也得等到最后一刻
I agree. I waited until the last possible moment.
当时红色警报已拉响，风暴愈演愈烈
We were on red alert. The storm got worse.
我不得不弃舱
I had to jettison the pod.
你怎么这么晚才到，史波克先生？
What took you so long, Mr. Spock?
舰长…
Captain...
- 我相信我… - 把它给我
- I believe I-- - I'll take that.
- 詹姆 - 原来你在这啊
- Jame. - There you are.
我只是想再多看你一眼
I just wanted one more look at you.
这个杀了我父亲的男人
The man who killed my father.
事情不是这样的，他是我的朋友
That's not so. He was my friend.
你的朋友？你这辈子都在厌恶他
Your friend? You hated him all your life,
这就是你杀他的原因，你这个凶手！
and that's why you killed him. You murderer!
你这个凶手，你这个凶手！
You murderer! You murderer!
詹姆
Jame.
史波克先生，麻烦请你…
Mr. Spock, would you please...?
芬尼小姐，请跟我来
Miss Finney, come with me, please.
寇克舰长
Captain Kirk,
你说你是在红色警报拉响后才弃舱的？
you say you jettisoned the pod after the red alert?
你这有我的证词
You have my sworn deposition.
那么，舰长，我必须假定你在故意作伪证
Then, captain, I must presume you have committed wilful perjury.
这份计算机的记录显示
This extract from your computer log says you jettisoned the pod
你是在红色警报拉响前弃舱的
before going to red alert.
不要离开基地
Consider yourself confined to the base.
官方调查后会确定是否需要最高军事法庭介入
An official enquiry will determine if a general court-martial is in order.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages Of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：madscientist 傻得雷
校对：诸星龟龟
第一季第二十集
军事法庭
舰长日志，星历2948.5
Captain's log, stardate 2948.5.
星舰进取号依旧停留在11号星际基地周围的轨道上
Starship Enterprise remains in orbit around Starbase 11.
所有的维修工作正在进行中
Full repairs in progress.
我被强制留在11号星际基地上
I have been ordered to stand by on Starbase 11
直到有关芬尼少校死亡的调查结果出来
until the enquiry into the death of Lieutenant Commander Finney can be conducted.
我对调查结果充满自信
I am confident of the outcome.
蒂摩西，自那次火山探险后就再没见过你了
Timothy, haven't seen you since the Vulcanian expedition.
看，我们军官学校
Well, I see our graduating
毕业班的学生也在场
class from the academy is well represented.
克里根，泰勒
Corrigan. Teller.
- 干得怎样，麦克？ - 一般般，吉姆
- How you doing, Mike? - I'll get by, Jim.
我了解为了维修你得暂留在这
I understand you're laying over for repairs.
大项目？
Big job?
- 就几天 - 然后就走了？
- Couple of days. - Be moving out then?
- 这么希望我走？ - 哦，我只是想知道要多久
- In a hurry to see me go? - Oh, I just wondered how long
你才会有一名新的记录官
it would take you to get a new records officer.
- 你可以说得再清楚点 - 我可以
- You can talk plainer than that. - I can.
但我刚才已把重点说出来了
But I think the point's been made.
- 本是我们的朋友 - 好了，吉姆，走吧
- Ben was a friend of ours. - Come on, Jim, let's go.
不，继续说完
No, go on, finish.
本是你们的朋友，然后…？
Ben was a friend of yours, and...?
吉姆
Jim.
继续
Go on.
- 我洗耳恭听 - 你为什么不告诉我们？
- I'm waiting to hear the rest. - Why don't you tell us?
什么才是重点？
What would be the point?
你们已做了决定
You've already made up your minds.
不好意思，老骨头
Excuse me, Bones.
如果你有任何疑虑
If you have any doubt
那肯定事关进取号的詹姆士·寇克舰长
that was indeed Captain James Kirk of the Enterprise.
我知道，你是他的朋友？
Yes, I know. Are you a friend of his?
在这段艰苦的时期，是他为数不多的朋友之一
In these trying times, one of the few.
伦纳德·麦考伊医生，你呢？
Dr. Leonard McCoy, and you?
艾利尔·肖
Areel Shaw.
我也是他的一位老朋友
And I'm a friend too. An old one.
我所有的老朋友看起来都像个医生
All of my old friends look like doctors.
他的老朋友看起来都像你
All of his look like you.
那么，你不如和我喝一杯
Well, you might as well join me for a drink.
随着调查的进行
With this enquiry coming up
他将需要所有他能交到的朋友
he's going to need all the friends he can get.
记录：调查
Recording: enquiry.
当事人：詹姆士·T·寇克舰长
Matter: Captain Kirk, James T.
内容：本杰明·芬尼少校的
Subject: circumstances of death,
死亡情形
Lieutenant Commander Finney, Benjamin.
这份调查将决定是否对寇克舰长
This enquiry to determine whether a general court-martial
召集最高军事法庭
should be convened against Captain Kirk,
以伪证罪和渎职罪对其指控
on charges of perjury and culpable negligence.
开始吧
Ready.
从你和芬尼少校的关系开始吧
Let's begin with your relationship with Commander Finney.
你认识他很久了吧？
You knew him for a long time, didn't you?
是的，在我还是一名学生时
Yes, he was an instructor at the academy when I was
他就在那当辅导员
a midshipman, but that didn't stand in the way
但这并不妨碍我们之间的友谊
of our beginning a close friendship.
他的女儿詹姆，昨晚在这的那位，就是以我的名字取名的
His daughter Jame, who was here last night, was named after me.
我们都知道你们之间曾发生过什么
It's common knowledge that something happened to your friendship.
这不是秘密，几年后我们被派到同一艘飞船上
It's no secret. We were assigned to the same ship some years later.
有次我替他值班
I relieved him on watch once
发现原子物质堆的控制电路开启了
and found a circuit open to the atomic matter piles
这本应处于关闭状态
that should've been closed.
再过五分钟整艘飞船就会被炸毁
Another five minutes, could have blown up the ship.
请说出飞船名称
Ship's nomenclature. specify.
联合共和国号，编号1371
United Starship Republic, number 1371.
继续
Continue.
我关了开关并将此事记录了下来
I closed the switch and logged the incident.
他遭到了斥责并被列入升职名单的末尾
He drew a reprimand and was sent to the bottom of the promotion list.
- 所以他因此责怪你？ - 是的
- And he blamed you for that? - Yes.
他在军官学校担任辅导员的时间
He had been at the academy for an unusually long time
异常漫长
as an instructor.
导致他很晚才被任命到飞船上
As a result, he was late in being assigned to a starship.
他感觉这在他的档案里看起来很糟糕
The delay, he felt, looked bad on his record.
他认为我的所作所为使他陷入更为糟糕的境地
My action, he believed, made things worse.
注记
Comment.
追加有关芬尼少校的工作记录
Service record of Commander Finney to be appended this enquiry.
记录生成
Noted.
现在来详细谈谈那次风暴吧，舰长
Now, let's get into the specifics of the storm, captain.
气象扫描仪显示离子风暴就在正前方
Weather scan indicated an ion storm dead ahead.
- 我派芬尼去了吊舱 - 为什么是芬尼？
- I sent Finney into the pod. - Why Finney?
- 恰好轮到他执勤 - 如果他想责怪
- He was top of the duty roster. - If he blamed--
他也许会责怪我，因为他从未驾驶过飞船
He may have blamed me that he never commanded a ship,
但我不会因为谁责怪我而改变分工
but I don't assign jobs on the basis of who blames me.
轮到芬尼了，我便叫他去了吊舱
It was Finney's turn, and I assigned him.
我和他刚到达吊舱…
He had just checked in with me...
…我们就撞上了风暴的前沿
...from the pod when we hit the leading edge of the storm.
一开始情况并不糟糕
Not too bad at first.
我拉响了黄色警报
I signalled a yellow alert.
但接着气压值，变异数，应力值
Then we began encountering pressure, variance, stress,
由于风暴的影响突然上升到7级
force seven, the works.
我最终拉响了红色警报
I finally signalled a red alert.
芬尼知道他大概只有几秒的时间
Finney knew he had a matter of seconds.
我也尽可能多给他几秒钟
I gave him those seconds and more.
但显然，这几秒完全不够
But, apparently, it wasn't enough.
那为什么，舰长，你船上计算机的自动记录显示
Then why, captain, does the computer log from your ship,
在你弃舱时
made automatically at the time, indicate that you were still on
只是拉响了黄色警报而不是红色警报？
yellow alert when you jettisoned, and not on red?
我不知道
I don't know.
- 肯定是什么地方出问题了 - 看起来貌似是这样
- There's been a mistake. - It would seem so.
计算机会出错吗？
Could the computer be wrong?
史波克先生正在验算结果
Mr. Spock is running a survey right now,
但这几乎不可能出错
but the odds are next to impossible.
停止记录
Stop recording.
看，吉姆
Now, look, Jim.
很少有人能像我俩一样
Not one man in a million could do what you and I have done.
指挥星舰
Command a starship.
每天都要做出上百个决策
A hundred decisions a day, hundreds of lives
数以百计的生命取决于你正确的决策
staked on you making every one of them right.
你已经累了，吉姆
You're played out, Jim.
- 筋疲力竭了 - 这就是你的看法？
- Exhausted. - Is that the way you see it?
如果你愿意合作，我就将这样汇报
It's the way my report will read, if you cooperate.
身体垮了，甚至精神都崩溃了？
Physical breakdown. Possibly even mental collapse?
- 也许 - 我会承认有人死了
- Possibly. - I'd be admitting that a man died--
什么也别承认，什么都别说
Admit nothing. Say nothing.
就让我们把事实就此掩盖吧
Let me bury the matter here and now.
从未有过星舰舰长受审，我不希望你成为第一人
No starship captain has ever stood trial before, and I don't want you to be first.
如果你的怀疑正确，我会感到内疚，我理应受到惩罚
If what you suspect is true, I'm guilty. I should be punished.
我在为军队考虑
I'm thinking of the service.
- 不会抹黑它的 - 通过什么手段，斯通准将？
- I won't have it smeared-- - By what, Commodore Stone?
好吧
All right.
通过一名明显的伪证者，他掩盖了自己的错误判断
By an evident perjurer who is either covering up his bad judgement,
- 自己的懦弱或是其他更糟的 - 到此为止，先生
- his cowardice or something worse. - That's as far as you go, sir.
我要告诉你当时我就在舰桥上
I'm telling you I was there, on the bridge.
我清楚发生了什么，我知道我做了什么
I know what happened. I know what I did.
就在记录里，计算机是不会撒谎的
It's in the transcript, and computer transcripts don't lie.
我告诉你，你要么接受永久地面调派
I'm telling you, either you accept a permanent ground assignment or...
否则就接受
...the whole disciplinary weight of Starfleet Command
- 星舰总部的纪律制裁吧 - 现在我们就是这么做的吗？
- will light right on your neck. - So that's the way we do it now?
让事实掩盖，连我一起
Sweep it under the rug and me along with it.
你休想，我要找出真相
Not on your life. I intend to fight.
那么你将遭到法庭的起诉
Then you draw a general court.
起诉？我强烈要求，现在就起诉我，斯通准将，就是现在
Draw it? I demand it. And right now, Commodore Stone. Right now.
舰长日志，星历2948.9
Captain's log, stardate 2948.9.
组成军事法庭委员会的成员们
The officers who will comprise my court-martial board
正前往11号星际基地
are proceeding to starbase 11.
同时，进取号的维修工作已接近尾声
Meanwhile, repairs on the Enterprise are almost complete.
艾利尔
Areel.
麦考伊医生说你在这
Dr. McCoy said you were here.
我本该通过空气就能察觉到，如静电般
I should have felt it in the air, like static electricity.
奉承使你无处不在
Flattery will get you everywhere.
已经…
It's been...
这样已经多久了？
How long has it been?
4年7个月零几天
Four years, seven months and an odd number of days.
- 我没有刻意去计时 - 你看起里还是那么的美丽
- Not that I'm counting. - You look marvellous.
你一点都没变
You haven't changed a bit.
但你变了，不是吗？
Things have changed for you, haven't they?
哦，你听说了，对吗？
Oh, you've heard about that, have you?
我是军法官办公室的一名律师，还记得吗？
I'm a lawyer in the Judge Advocate's office, remember?
我还记得，不提了
I remember. Let's forget it.
我们错过了很长时间，要尽力弥补
We have a lot of lost time to make up for.
你把它看得很轻
You're taking it very lightly.
- 一个无辜男人的信心 - 是这样吗？
- The confidence of an innocent man. - Are you?
传闻可不是这么说的
That's not what the rumours indicate.
好了，不要三句不离本行
Look, let's not talk shop.
吉姆，这会毁了你的，你会接受建议吗？
Jim, this could ruin you. Will you take some advice?
我永远都无法说服你
I never could talk you into anything.
好的，我们开始吧
All right, fire away.
检察官的立案基础
The prosecution will build its case on the basis of Kirk
就是寇克与计算机
versus the computer.
如果你的律师想要对此辩护
Now, if your attorney tries to defend on that basis,
你是没有机会的
you won't have a chance.
还有别的选择吗？
What other choice is there?
这取决于你的律师，所以他得足够的优秀
Well, that's up to your attorney, and that's why he's got to be a good one.
- 也许，你能办到？ - 不，我…
- You, perhaps? - No, I...
- 我很忙 - 好吧
- I'm busy. - Well,
像你这般优秀的女性是有能力同时处理两个案件的
a girl with your ability should be able to handle two cases at once.
吉姆，严肃点
Jim, be serious.
你的身份不一般，你是一舰之长
You're not an ordinary human. You're a starship captain,
你正陷入丑门
and you've stepped into scandal.
他们不会放过任何能拉你下台的机会
If there's any way they can do it, they'll slap you down
一切都是为了维护军队的利益
hard and permanently for the good of the service.
你还没有给我任何的建议
You still haven't made any recommendations.
塞缪尔·T·科格利律师
Samuel T. Cogley, attorney at law.
如果有人能够救你，就是他了
If anyone can save you, he can.
他会去拜访你的
He'll be paying you a visit.
- 吉姆，我必须走了 - 艾利尔
- Jim, I've got to go. - Areel.
你还没告诉我你是怎么得到这么多
You still haven't told me how you know so much
有关检察官如何行动的信息的
about what the prosecution's going to do.
因为，吉姆·寇克，我的旧爱
Because, Jim Kirk, my dear old love...
我就是那名检察官
...I am the prosecution.
我必须尽我所能将你狠狠的拉下台
And I have to do my very best to have you slapped down hard,
让你可耻地
broken out of the service,
离开军队
in disgrace.
是寇克吗？
You Kirk?
是我
Yes.
这都是些什么？
What is all this?
我发现我们得共处一段时间
I figured we'd be spending some time together
所以我搬了过来
so I moved in.
我希望没有挤到你
I hope I'm not crowding you.
怎么了，你不喜欢书吗？
What's the matter, don't you like books?
不，我很喜欢，不过电脑占地更少
Oh, I like them fine, but a computer takes less space.
电脑？
A computer, huh?
我从办公室带了台过来
I got one of these in my office.
里面储存了所有的案例
Contains all the precedents.
涵盖了过去到现在所有最出色的法律决策
A synthesis of all the great legal decisions written throughout time.
我从来不用它
I never use it.
为什么？
Why not?
我有自己的系统
I've got my own system.
这些书，年轻人，书
Books, young man, books.
成千上万的书
Thousands of them.
如果时间充裕，我会给你看些东西
lf time wasn't so important, I'd show you something.
我的图书馆，成千上万本书
My library. Thousands of books.
到底有什么用？
What would be the point?
这就是法律的所在
This is where the law is.
不是那种均匀化、巴氏消毒式、合成类…
Not in that homogenised, pasteurised, synthesised...
你想了解法律吗？
Do you want to know the law? The ancient concepts
用其特有语言诉说的古老概念？
in their own language? Learn the intent of the men
了解制定者的意图？从摩西到阿尔法3号的法庭？
who wrote them? From Moses to the Tribunal of Alpha III?
都在这些书里
Books.
你要么是逃离监护人的强迫症疯子
You have to be either an obsessive crackpot who's escaped
要么就是塞缪尔·T·科格利律师
from his keeper or Samuel T. Cogley, attorney at law.
都被你说对了，需要律师吗？
You're right on both counts. Need a lawyer?
恐怕需要
I'm afraid so.
法庭现在正式开庭
This court is now in session.
我已任命以下人员为该庭审判员
I have appointed, as members of this court...
太空司令部代表林斯特罗姆
...Space Command Representative Lindstrom...
星舰舰长考茨基和香德拉
...Starship Captains Krasnovsky and Chandra.
寇克舰长，请注意一个事实
Captain Kirk, I direct your attention to the fact
如果你认为上述人员在此次事件上对你持有偏见
that you have a right to ask for substitute officers if you feel
你有权要求替换审判员
that any of these named harbour prejudiced attitudes to your case.
我没任何异议，长官
I have no objection, sir.
你是否同意肖上尉
And do you consent to the service of Lieutenant Shaw
作为这次的检察官，以及我作为法官？
as prosecuting officer, and to myself as president of the court?
我同意，长官
I do, sir.
一切就绪，书记员
All right, clerk.
指控：重大过失
Charge: culpable negligence.
详述：星历2945.7
Specification: In that, on stardate 2945.7
舰长詹姆士·T·寇克由于疏忽
by such negligence, Captain Kirk, James T.
导致记录官
did cause loss of life to wit, the life of records officer
本杰明·芬尼少校死亡
Lieutenant Commander Finney, Benjamin.
对于上诉控告，有何辩解？
To all recorded charges and specifications, what is the plea?
我不承认有罪
Not guilty.
继续，上尉
Proceed, lieutenant.
请史波克先生陈述
I call Mr. Spock.
史波克：编号S 179-276 SP
Spock: serial number S 179-276 SP.
头衔：少校
Service rank: lieutenant commander.
职位：大副兼科学官
Position: first officer, science officer.
当前任职处：联邦星舰进取号
Current Assignment: USS Enterprise.
荣誉：瓦肯科学荣誉勋章
Commendations: Vulcanian Scientific Legion of Honor.
勇气奖：两次被星舰总部授勋
Awards of valour: twice decorated by starfleet Command.
史波克先生，作为大副
Mr. Spock, as a first officer you know a great deal
你肯定对计算机相当了解，对吗？
about computers, don't you?
我完全了解
I know all about them.
计算机是有可能发生故障的，对吗？
It is possible for a computer to malfunction, is it not?
是的
Affirmative.
你是否知道进取号的计算机
Do you know of any malfunction
曾出现过故障导致不准确的情况？
which has caused an inaccuracy in the Enterprise computer?
没有
Negative.
你的回答是基于本次审讯前
That answer is based on your mechanical survey
被告下令进行的
of the Enterprise computer, ordered by
进取号计算机机械调查，对吗？
the defendant prior to this trial, is it not?
是的
Affirmative.
现在，星历…
Now, the stardate--
尽管如此，计算机还是不准确的
But the computer is inaccurate, nevertheless.
为什么这样说？
Why do you say that?
记录显示弃舱按钮是在红色警报拉响前被按下的
It reports that the jettison button was pressed before the red alert.
也就是说，关于寇克舰长
In other words, it reports that Captain Kirk
应对紧急情况的报告是不存在的
was reacting to an extreme emergency that did not then exist.
那是不可能的
And that is impossible.
是吗？
Is it?
难道你当时在场亲眼看到
Were you watching him the exact moment
他按下弃舱按钮了？
he pressed the jettison button?
不，我当时无暇顾及
No. I was occupied.
飞船已进入黄色预警状态
The ship was already on yellow alert.
那这份记录你为何还能提出异议？
Then how can you dispute the finding of the log?
我没有异议
I do not dispute it.
我只是想说这记录有问题
I merely state that it is wrong.
哦？
Oh?
你凭什么这样说？
On what do you base that statement?
我了解舰长
I know the captain.
- 他是…  - 请给出证据，不要凭空猜测
- He is in--  - Please instruct the witness, not to speculate.
上尉
Lieutenant.
我也算半个瓦肯人
I am half Vulcanian.
瓦肯人是不会凭空猜测的
Vulcanians do not speculate.
我只是通过纯粹的逻辑进行说明
I speak from pure logic.
如果我让锤子在有重力的星球上下落
If I let go of a hammer on a planet that has a positive gravity,
我不必看也知道它会下落，事实上，它已经落地了
I need not see it fall to know that it has, in fact, fallen.
- 我不认为这能说明什么 - 先生们
- I do not see what that has-- - Gentlemen,
人类和无生命体有某些共同的特点
human beings have characteristics just as inanimate objects do.
寇克舰长是不可能出于恐慌或恶意才这样做的
It is impossible for Captain Kirk to act out of panic or malice.
这不是他的本性
It is not his nature.
这只是你个人的观点
In your opinion.
是的
Yes.
只是我个人的观点
In my opinion.
谢谢
Thank you.
对此还有什么疑问吗，科格利先生
Your witness, Mr. Cogley.
没问题
No questions.
你可以归位了
You may step down.
现在请进取号的人事官陈述
I now call the personnel officer for the Enterprise.
头衔：少尉
Service rank: ensign.
职位：人事官
Position: personnel officer.
当前任职处：联邦星舰进取号
Current assignment: USS Enterprise.
在你担任进取号人事官期间
In the course of your duties as personnel officer of the Enterprise,
你应该对船上所有人的工作记录都非常的熟悉吧？
you would be familiar with the service records of all aboard?
是的，女士
Yes, ma'am.
关于记录官芬尼
With reference to Records Officer Finney
他的工作记录中
was there in his service record
是否有一份因未关闭电路而受到纪律处分的报告？
a report of disciplinary action for failure to close a circuit?
是的，女士
Yes, ma'am.
那时候的处分
Was the charge, in that instance,
是依据替班人的日志记录吗？
based upon a log entry by the officer who relieved him?
是的，女士
Yes, ma'am.
那个人是谁？
And who was that officer?
詹姆士·T·寇克少尉
Ensign James T. Kirk.
请大声说，这里是法庭
Louder, please, for the court.
詹姆士·T·寇克少尉
Ensign James T. Kirk.
就是坐在这个法庭里的寇克舰长吗？
Now the Captain Kirk who sits in this courtroom?
是的，女士
Yes, ma'am.
谢谢
Thank you.
你还有什么想问的吗，科格利先生？
Do you wish to cross-examine, Mr. Cogley?
没问题
No questions.
你可以归位了
You may step down.
请麦考伊医生上来陈述
I now call Dr. McCoy to the stand.
头衔：少校
Service rank: lieutenant commander.
职位：船医
Position: ship's surgeon.
当前任职处：联邦星舰进取号
Current assignment: USS Enterprise.
荣誉：荣誉勋章
Commendation: Legion of Honor.
勇气奖：由星际舰队医疗部授勋
Awards of valour: decorated by Starfleet surgeons.
医生，根据记录，你是心理学专家
Doctor, you are, on the record, an expert in psychology,
特别擅长外太空漫长航程中
especially space psychology patterns which develop
产生于相近舱房的空间心理学模式
in the close quarters of a ship during long voyages in deep space.
对此我了解一些
I know something about it.
你刚才也听到了你们人事官的证词
You have just heard the testimony of your own personnel officer
是那时的寇克少尉
that it was an action of the then Ensign Kirk
造成了芬尼上尉记录上不可抹去的污点
which placed an un-erasable blot on the record
从心理上分析，医生
of the then Lieutenant Finney. Psychologically, doctor,
芬尼上尉会不会因此责怪寇克？
is it possible that Lieutenant Finney blamed Kirk for the incident?
有可能
It's possible.
在接下来的几年，他可能会一直记恨着寇克
He could have hated Kirk, down through the years,
得不到升迁，从未执掌过指挥棒
blamed him for being passed over for promotion,
将这一切归咎于他，对吧？
blamed him for never being given a command of his own, correct?
- 可能 - 那么，让我们做个假设，医生
- He could have. - Now, let us hypothesise, doctor.
以德报怨正常吗？
Is it normal for a person to return affection for hatred?
- 不正常 - 对憎恨我们的人，我们是否倾向于
- No. - Do we not tend to, at first, resent,
一开始不满，然后极其厌恶？
and then actively dislike the person who hates us?
等等，我不太明白你的意思
Wait a minute, I don't quite follow you.
假设下
Hypothetically,
史密斯舰长是否会开始厌恶琼斯少校
would not Captain Smith begin to hate Lieutenant Commander Jones
一旦他得知琼斯少校
once he learned that Lieutenant Commander Jones
讨厌、憎恶他？
hated and detested him?
对，我觉得可能
Oh, yes, I suppose it could happen.
那么我问你
Then I ask you,
可不可能寇克舰长意识到了
is it not possible that Captain Kirk became aware
芬尼少校对他的仇恨
of Lieutenant Commander Finney's hatred toward him
也许，甚至是无心地开始回敬了呢？
and perhaps, even involuntarily, began to reciprocate?
寇克舰长不可能
Not Captain Kirk.
以正常人来看，医生
Any normal human, doctor.
可能吗？
Is it possible?
但他不是那种人
But he's not that kind of a man.
理论上是否可能，医生？
Is it theoretically possible, doctor?
是
Yes.
可能
It's possible.
谢谢
Thank you.
该你了，科格利先生
Your witness, Mr. Cogley.
没问题
No questions.
你可以退下了
You may step down.
科格利先生
Mr. Cogley,
你已经听取了三位证人的证词
you have listened to testimony from three witnesses,
每一次你都没有利用
and in neither instance have you availed yourself
你的反诘问权
of your right to cross-examine.
你是否放弃这个权利？
Have you abrogated that right?
阁下，事实上
Well, sir, the truth is
我一直忍着等热身运动结束
I've been holding back till we get this preliminary business out of the way.
我想提请寇克舰长上庭
I'd like to call Captain Kirk to the stand.
詹姆士·T·寇克
James T. Kirk.
编号SC 937-0176 CEC
Serial number SC 937-0176 CEC.
头衔：舰长 职位：星舰指挥官
Service rank: captain. Position: starship command.
当前分配：联邦星舰进取号
Current assignment: USS Enterprise.
荣誉：阿克萨那和平行动棕榈叶奖章
Commendations: Palm Leaf of Axanar Peace Mission,
格兰凯特战术奖章，特等
Grankite Order of Tactics, Class of Excellence.
普伦特斯绶带，一等及二等——
Prentares Ribbon of Commendation, Classes First and Second--
庭上，请允许我…
May it please the court.
法庭同意检察官请求
Court recognises counsel for the prosecution.
检察官承认寇克舰长的卓越履历
The prosecution concedes the inestimable record of Captain Kirk.
科格利律师？
Mr. Cogley?
我不想阻碍前进的车轮
I wouldn't want to slow the wheels of progress.
但另一方面
But then, on the other hand,
我也不想让这些车轮恣意匆匆
I wouldn't want those wheels to run over my client
碾过我的委托人
in their unbridled haste.
继续
Continue.
勇气奖：荣誉勋章，多枚银质棕榈勋章
Awards of valour: Medal of Honor, silver Palm with Cluster,
星际舰队英勇卓越表彰
Starfleet Citation for Conspicuous Gallantry,
- 卡拉盖特勋章 - 停
- Karagite Order of-- - Stop.
我觉得差不多了
I think that's enough.
我可不想碍太多事
I wouldn't wanna slow things up too much.
谢谢
Thank you.
那么舰长，不管这些机器说了什么
Now, captain, despite what these machines indicate,
在你弃舱之前，真的已经红色警报了吗？
was there indeed a red alert before you jettisoned the pod?
是的，有
Yes, sir, there was.
跟我们谈谈吧
Please tell us about it.
首先，我无法理解计算机提取出来的记录
Firstly, I am at a loss to explain the errors
会出现错误
in the extract from the computer log.
我们遇到了离子风暴
We were in an ion storm.
这个庭上的每个人都明白它的危险
Everyone here in this court knows the dangers involved.
我在指挥
I was in command.
决定是我做出的，而非其他人
The decisions were mine, no one else's.
预谋的罪名指向我，但没有预谋
Charges of malice have been raised. There was no malice.
芬尼少校是我舰上的一员
Lieutenant Commander Finney was a member of my crew,
我也正是如此待他
and that's exactly the way he was treated.
有人认为我在舰桥上慌张了
It has been suggested that I panicked on the bridge
过早地抛弃了隔舱，事实不是那样的
and jettisoned the ion pod prematurely. That is not so.
你们也听到了我履历里的一些细节
You have heard some of the details of my record.
这并不是我遇到的第一次险情
This was not my first crisis.
这只是九牛一毛
It was one of many.
其间
During it
我所作所为是我的经验和训练所要求的
I did what my experience and training required me to do.
我以适当的次序采取了适当的行动
I took the proper steps in the proper order.
我正是在该做的时候
I did exactly what had to be done,
做了该做的事情
exactly when it should have been done.
你做了正确的事情，但你下次还会这么做吗？
You did the right thing, but would you do it again?
如果是在同样的情况下…
Given the same circumstances...
…我会毫不犹豫地再做一次同样的事情
...I would do the same thing without hesitation.
因为我采取的行动
Because the steps I took,
和行动的次序
in the order I took them,
都是绝对必要的，如果我要救我的星舰
were absolutely necessary if I were to save my ship.
而没有任何事情
And nothing
比我的星舰更重要
is more important than my ship.
轮到你了，肖女士
Your witness, Miss Shaw.
检察官并不想侮慢这位先生
The prosecution does not wish to dishonour this man
但事实就是事实
but facts are facts.
我必须要提请庭上和寇克舰长注意
I must invite the attention of the court and Captain Kirk
从进取号电脑记录里提取出的视频资料
to this visual extract from the Enterprise computer log.
播放
Playback.
你们即将看到的正是离子风暴期间
What you are about to see is precisely what took place
进取号舰桥上发生的事情
on the Enterprise bridge during the ion storm.
气象报告离子风暴即将到来，舰长
Meteorology reports ion storm upcoming, captain.
我们需要有人去隔舱读取读数，史波克
We'll need somebody in the pod for readings, Mr. Spock.
- 执勤表上第一位是芬尼先生 - 派他去吧
- Mr. Finney is top of duty roster. - Post him.
- 上尉 - 请注意，芬尼少校
- Lieutenant. - Attention, Commander Finney.
请到隔舱报到读取离子板上的读数
Report to pod for reading on ionplates.
- 收到 - 人员到岗，舰长
- Message received. - Officer posted, captain.
- 准备警戒状态，史波克 - 收到
- Stand by on alert status, Mr. Spock. - Acknowledged.
接近离子风暴，长官
Approaching ion storm, sir.
- 曲速1级，汉森 - 曲速1级，长官
- Warp factor 1, Mr. Hansen. - Warp 1, sir.
倒退
Reverse.
停
Stop.
放大仪表板，继续
Go forward with magnification on the panel.
重力控制切换到电池
Gravity control switching to batteries.
停下
Freeze that.
寇克舰长现在发出了黄色警报
Captain Kirk is now signalling a yellow alert.
继续，标准视图
Go forward, normal view.
- 隔舱呼叫，长官 - 接进来
- Call from the pod, sir. - Tie in.
这里是芬尼，舰长，正在读取离子读数
Finney here, captain. Ion readings in progress.
快一点，本，我可能要上红色警报了
Make it fast, Ben. I may have to go to red alert.
收到
Affirmative.
- 保持航向，汉森 - 遵命，长官
- Hold your course, Mr. Hansen. - Aye, aye, sir.
横向振动，二级，舰长
Lateral vibrations, force two, captain.
- 三级 - 轮机舱，然后离子隔舱
- Force three. - Engineering, then ion pod.
遵命，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
- 轮机舱 - 加三分之一推力
- Engineering. - One-third more thrust.
运转中
Working.
离子隔舱
Ion pod.
随时准备离开，本
Stand by to get out of there, Ben.
遵命，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
五级，长官
Force five, sir.
保持平稳，汉森
Steady as she goes, Mr. Hansen.
停下
Freeze that.
庭上注意到的话
If the court will notice
记录很明白地显示了
the log plainly shows
被告的手指按着投弃的按钮
the defendant's finger pressing the jettison button.
而仪表盘上显示的是黄色警报，而非红色警报
The condition signal reads yellow alert, not red alert,
黄色警报，明白无误
but simply yellow alert.
载有芬尼少校的隔舱被抛弃时
When the pod containing Lieutenant Commander Finney was jettisoned,
紧急情况并未发生
the emergency did not as yet exist.
但事情不是这样的
But that's not the way it happened.
舰长日志，星历2949.9
Captain's log, stardate 2949.9.
呈给最高军事法庭的视频资料证据
The evidence presented by the visual playback to my general court-martial
糟糕透顶，我觉得连我的律师都开始怀疑我了
was damning. I suspect even my attorney has begun to doubt me.
计算机不会撒谎
Computers don't lie.
那你就是说我撒谎了？
Are you suggesting that I did?
我是说你可能的确有失误
I'm suggesting that maybe you did have a lapse.
这是可能的，在你所受的压力下
It was possible, you know, with the strain you were under.
还有时间来修改抗辩，我可以让你脱身
There's still time to change our plea. I could get you off.
两天前，我还会把赌注全都押在自己的判断上
Two days ago, I'd have staked anything on my judgement.
你赌了，你的职业生涯
You did. Your professional career.
我的一生都在训练做那样的决定
I spent my whole life training for decisions just like that one.
穷其一生
My whole life.
可不可能那时候…？
Is it possible that when the moment came...?
不可能
No.
我知道我做了什么
I know what I did.
你可以抽身，如果愿意
You can pull out if you want to.
无处可逃啊，除非回法庭
There's no place to go, except back to court
听取判决
and hear the verdict.
- 我是寇克 - 舰长
- Kirk here. - Captain.
我对计算机进行了事无巨细的全面体检
I have run a complete megalite survey on the computer.
我来宣布你的发现吧，什么都没发现，对吧？
I'll tell you what you found. Nothing, right?
您的声音很苦，舰长
You sound bitter, captain.
还没苦到不懂得谢你的努力
Not bitter enough to forget to thank you for your efforts.
进一步的指示？
Further instructions?
没有了
No.
这一切没有想象的那么糟，史波克
It's not all bad, Mr. Spock.
谁知道呢？
Who knows?
也许你可以在象棋上击败下一任舰长
You may be able to beat your next captain at chess.
寇克，挂了
Kirk, out.
象棋
Chess.
詹姆
Jame.
这是芬尼的女儿
This is Finney's daughter.
- 芬尼小姐 -科格利律师，你必须得阻止他
- Miss Finney. - Mr. Cogley, you've got to stop this.
让他接受地面任务吧
Make him take a ground assignment.
我意识到这并不是他的错
I realise it wasn't his fault.
我不会再捣乱了
I won't make any trouble.
- 让他修改抗辩吧 - 太迟了，詹姆
- Make him change his plea. - It's too late for that, Jame.
但是我很高兴你不再把发生的一切归咎于我
But I'm glad you don't blame me anymore for what happened.
那天晚上我太沮丧了，对不起
I was just so upset that night. I'm sorry.
别多说了
Don't say anymore.
但我必须得说
But I have to.
我从未意识到你和爸爸以前是多么亲密
I never realised how close you and Dad had been
直到我读到他写过的一些信
until I read through some of the papers he wrote.
给妈妈和我的信
Letters to Mother and me.
我不知道我怎么能那样想…
I don't know how I ever could have thought that you...
科格利律师，覆水难收，毁掉吉姆也无济于事
Mr. Cogley, ruining Jim won't change what's happened.
你的行为可圈可点，芬尼小姐，但非比寻常
That's very commendable, Miss Finney, but most unusual.
毕竟，寇克舰长被指控导致你父亲的死亡
After all, Captain Kirk is accused of causing your father's death.
而证据也显示他有罪
And the evidence would indicate his guilt.
我只是为吉姆着想
I was just thinking of Jim.
明白，非常感谢
I know, and I thank you.
我得走了，你准备好了吗？
I have to go and change. You ready?
没
No,
不过可能慢慢就准备好了
but I may be getting ready.
飞象
Bishop, half level right.
好吧，不是亲眼所见我是不会相信的
Well, I had to see it to believe it.
说明一下
Explain.
他们就要腰斩舰长的职业生涯
They're gonna lop off the captain's professional head,
而你却在这里和计算机下象棋
and you're sitting here playing chess with a computer.
对
That is true.
史波克先生，你是我见过的最冷血的人
Mr. Spock, you're the most cold-blooded man I've ever known.
哎呀，谢谢，医生
Why, thank you, doctor.
我刚赢了第四局
I've just won my fourth game.
不可能
That's impossible.
自己看
Observe for yourself.
进車
Rook to king's pawn four.
飞象
Bishop, half level right.
这是计算机的走法
Now, this is the computer's move.
然后是我
And now mine.
将军
Checkmate.
技术上而言，计算机没有缺点
Mechanically, the computer is flawless.
所以从逻辑上来说，它举证舰长有罪是没有错的
Therefore, logically, its report of the captain's guilt is infallible.
但是我不能接受这种说法
I could not accept that, however.
所以你就测试了程序库
So you tested the programme bank.
对，几个月前我亲自设置了象棋程序
Exactly. I programmed it myself for chess some months ago.
我能做到的最好结果应该是平局
The best I should have been able to obtain was a draw.
那你还坐在这里干嘛呢？
Well, why are you just sitting there?
传送室，准备，我们马上下去
Transporter Room, stand by. We're beaming down.
现在开庭
Court is now in session.
在发布判决前，委员会欢迎提案
The board will entertain motions before delivering its verdict.
检察官？
Counsel for the prosecution?
大人，检察官完毕
Sir, the prosecution rests.
被告律师？
Counsel for the defence?
大人…
Sir...
…被告完毕
...the defence rests.
科格利律师
Mr. Cogley.
大人
Sir.
刚刚发现新的证据
Some new evidence has just been brought to my attention,
我请求庭上
and I'd like to ask the court to
抗议
Objection.
被告律师对此案件已经完毕
Counsel for the defence has rested his case.
这个证据是什么性质？
- Of what nature is this evidence?
无可奉告，只能展示给您，大人
I can't tell you, I have to show you, sir.
科格利律师的表演天赋广为人知
Mr. Cogley is well-known for his theatrics.
拯救一个无辜者的职业生涯是表演吗？
Is saving an innocent man's career a theatric?
律师请将评论传达给法官席
Counsels will kindly direct their remarks to the bench.
十分乐意，大人
I'd be delighted to, sir
既然我可以谈谈人情了
Now that I've got something human to talk about.
权利，大人，人权，圣经
Rights, sir, human rights. The Bible.
汉谟拉比法典，查士丁尼法典
The Code of Hammurabi and of Justinian.
大宪章，美国宪法
Magna Carta. The Constitution of the United States.
火星殖民地的基本宣言
Fundamental Declarations of the Martian Colonies.
阿尔法三号星章程
The Statutes of Alpha III.
先生们…
Gentlemen...
…这些文件都在谈权利
...these documents all speak of rights.
被告和同伴接受审理的权利
Rights of the accused to a trial by his peers.
有律师为之辩护的权利
To be represented by counsel.
质证的权利，但最重要的是
The rights of cross-examination. But most importantly,
对抗不利证人的权利
the right to be confronted by the witnesses against him.
而我的委托人却没有享受这个权利
A right to which my client has been denied.
法官大人，这很荒谬
Your Honour, that is ridiculous.
我们在庭上呈上证人
We produced the witnesses in court.
我经验丰富的对手有机会观察他们
My learned opponent had the opportunity to see them,
- 盘诘他们—— - 还有一个证人
- cross-examine them-- - All but one.
对我委托人有毁灭性影响的证人并不是人类
The most devastating witness against my client is not a human being.
是机器
It's a machine.
一个信息系统，进取号的电脑记录
An information system. The computer log of the Enterprise.
我提请休庭，去舰上重新开庭
And I ask this court adjourn and reconvene aboard that vessel.
- 我抗议，法官大人 - 我重复一遍，我在说权利
- I protest, Your Honour. - And I repeat. I speak of rights.
机器没有权利，人必须有
A machine has none. A man must.
我的委托人有权利面对原告
My client has the right to face his accuser.
如果你们不赋予他这个权利
And if you do not grant him that right,
你们就把我们拉低到机器的层级
you have brought us down to the level of the machine.
确实，你们已经将机器奉若神明
Indeed, you have elevated that machine above us.
我要求我的请求得到同意
I ask that my motion be granted.
不仅如此，先生们
And more than that, gentlemen.
以一个在机器阴影下枯萎的人类的名义
In the name of a humanity fading in the shadow of the machine,
我有权要求，我必须要求
I demand it. I demand it.
舰长日志，星历2950.1
Captain's log, stardate 2950.1.
经过适当考虑，最高军事法庭在
After due consideration, the general court-martial has reconvened
进取号上重新开庭
onboard the Enterprise.
你赢了电脑几局象棋，史波克先生？
How many games of chess did you win from the computer, Mr. Spock?
总共五次
Five in all.
那是非比寻常的吗？
May that be considered unusual?
对
Affirmative.
为什么？
Why?
我自己几个月前给电脑设置了象棋程序
I personally programmed the computer for chess months ago.
我赋予了计算机相当于我自己的象棋水平
I gave the machine an understanding of the game equal to my own.
计算机不可能出错，然后假定我也不出错
The computer cannot make an error, and assuming that I do not either,
通常可以期待的最好结果就是僵局
the best that could normally be hoped for would be stalemate
接着僵局
after stalemate.
然而我还是打败了计算机五次
And yet I beat the machine five times.
有人，不管是无意还是有意
Someone, either accidentally or deliberately,
调整过程序，进而
adjusted the programming, and therefore,
影响到计算机的内存库
the memory banks of that computer.
那这对我们看到的视频资料有影响吗？
Could that have had an effect on the visual playback we saw?
反对，证人在做结论
Object. The witness would be making a conclusion.
同意
Sustained.
假设，史波克先生
Hypothetically, Mr. Spock.
假设，肖女士
Hypothetically, Miss Shaw.
如果你们所暗示的行为确实存在
If what you suggest had been done,
这种能力也非常人所及
it would be beyond the capabilities of most men.
对吗？
Is that true?
对
Affirmative.
舰上的哪些人有这样的能力呢？
What man aboard ship would it not be beyond?
舰长，我
The captain, myself
还有记录官
and the records officer.
而现在，你们没有记录官
And at the moment, you have no records officer.
对，直到他消失之前
Affirmative. Until he was lost
我们的记录官一直是芬尼少校
our records officer was Lieutenant Commander Finney.
寇克舰长
Captain Kirk
你能讲讲在风暴之后
will you tell the steps you took to
你采取了哪些行动来寻找芬尼先生吗？
find Mr. Finney after the storm?
我发起了一次一阶段搜寻
I instituted a Phase 1 Search.
描述一下一阶段搜寻
Describe a Phase 1 Search.
是在舰上及周围寻找一位可能已受伤不能回应的人员
It's a painstaking, thorough attempt, in and around the ship,
这是一种辛苦而彻底的尝试
to find a man who is presumably injured and unable to respond.
这是否假定这个人愿意被找到？
It presupposes, does it not, that a man wishes to be found?
对不起没太听懂
I beg your pardon?
如果你开始寻找一个人
If you start a search for a man,
你是否会假定他想被找到？他没有藏起来
you assume, don't you, that he wants to be found? He's not hiding.
是
Yes.
在这么大一艘舰船上
On a ship of this size
一个人能逃脱这样的搜寻吗？
could a man evade such a search?
可能
Possibly.
先生们
Gentlemen,
我主张，本·芬尼少校并没有死
I submit to you that Lieutenant Commander Ben Finney is not dead.
科格利律师，我们等着你在简报室做出的
Mr. Cogley, we are waiting for proof of the extraordinary statement
这个惊人陈述的证据
you made in the briefing room.
你们会看到的
And you shall have it.
但首先我需要法庭在一次实验中的合作
But first I need the cooperation of this court in conducting an experiment.
寇克舰长
Captain Kirk.
先生们
Gentlemen.
为了这次实验之便，有必要让全体人员
For the purposes of this experiment, it will be necessary for all personnel,
除了法庭成员和指挥人员
except for members of the court and the command crew,
离开舰船，我命令其他人都去
to leave the ship. I am ordering all others to report
- 传送室报到 - 包括我，大人
- to the Transporter Room. - Including myself, sir.
绝不休庭，科格利律师
This court is by no means adjourned, Mr. Cogley.
我在地上有个差事
I have an errand ashore of vital importance
对这次法庭极其重要，我会回来的
to the purpose of this court, and I will return.
很好
Very well.
谢谢大人
Thank you, sir.
舰长，舰上有发动机人员吗？
Captain, are you maintaining an engine crew aboard?
我们的脉冲引擎已经关闭了
Our impulse engines have been shut down.
我们会依靠动量保持轨道
We'll maintain orbit by momentum.
轨道什么时候开始衰变呢？
And when the orbit begins to decay?
我们希望能早在那之前就结束
We hope to be finished long before then.
好了吗，史波克？
Ready, Mr. Spock?
好了，舰长
Affirmative, captain.
先生们，这个计算机有听觉感应器
Gentlemen, this computer has an auditory sensor.
实际上，它可以听到声音
It can, in effect, hear sounds.
只要安装扩爆器，我们就可以提升其性能
By installing a booster, we can increase that capability
呈现一到四级的功率
on the order of one to the fourth power.
计算机应该能将这艘舰上的每一个声音呈现给我们
The computer should be able to bring us every sound occurring on the ship.
全体人员都已遵照命令离开舰船，长官
All personnel have left the ship as ordered, sir.
麦考伊医生？
Dr. McCoy?
好了，史波克
All right, Mr. Spock.
声音调小点
Turn it down a little.
先生们，这声音是舰上
Gentlemen, that sound is caused by the heartbeats
所有人的心跳声
of all the people onboard the ship.
麦考伊医生
Dr. McCoy
会用这个消声器来遮盖每个人的心跳声
will use this white-sound device to mask out each person's
这样我们听到的声音里就不会有那声音了
heartbeat so that it will be eliminated from the sounds we are hearing.
首先，舰长
First, the captain.
史波克
Mr. Spock.
最后，是我自己
And lastly, myself.
我们所有人都消了，除了传送室的工作人员
That's all of us, except the crewman in the Transporter Room.
史波克，消掉他的心跳声
Mr. Spock, eliminate his heartbeat.
那就是所有人了
That accounts for everyone.
芬尼
Finney.
定位这声音
Localise that.
B甲板，轮机室区域
B Deck. In or near Engineering.
封锁B甲板，18-Y到23-D区
Seal off B Deck, sections 18-Y through 23-D.
收到
Acknowledged.
所以芬尼还活着
So Finney is alive.
看起来是这样
It would seem so.
准将，这是我的私事
Commodore, this is my problem.
如果没人离开舰桥，我会十分感激
I would appreciate it if no one left the bridge.
塞缪尔·科格利去地上接詹姆·芬尼上船了
Sam Cogley had gone ashore to bring Jame Finney onboard.
我们都觉得詹姆在的话，处理芬尼会更容易
We both felt that Jame's presence would make Finney easier to handle
如果芬尼真的还活着的话
in the event Finney really were alive.
本
Ben.
本·芬尼
Ben Finney.
史波克，有异动
Mr. Spock, encountering variance.
- 抵消 - 什么意思？
- Compensate. - What does that mean?
轨道开始衰变了
The orbit is beginning to decay.
本，你在哪儿？
Ben, where are you?
你好啊，舰长
Hello, captain.
无话可说么，舰长？
Nothing to say, captain?
很高兴你还活着
I'm glad you're alive.
觉得自己的职业生涯得到拯救
You mean you're relieved
所以你可以如释重负了
because you think your career is saved.
那你就错了
Well, you're wrong.
本
Ben.
本，还来得及，我们可以帮你
Ben, it's not too late. We can help you.
就像你一直以来帮我那样？
Like you helped me all along?
把我踩在脚下
Kept me down.
抢走了我的指挥棒
Robbed me of my own command.
我是个好长官，和你旗鼓相当
I'm a good officer. As good as you.
我观察了你好些年了
I've watched you for years.
英雄舰长寇克
The great Captain Kirk.
他们指示你对我动手脚
They told you to do it to me.
你们都阴谋陷害我，你们毁了我
You all conspired against me. You ruined me.
但是你不能再继续了
But you won't do it anymore.
把枪放下，本
Put the phaser down, Ben.
我不会杀你的，舰长
Oh, I wouldn't kill you, captain.
你自己的死对我来说一文不值
Your own death would mean too little to you.
但你的舰船——
But your ship--
我的舰船怎么了？
What about my ship?
它死了，我杀的
It's dead. I've killed it.
我破坏了你们的首要供能电路
I tapped out your primary energy circuits.
史波克，我们的轨道状况怎么样？
Mr. Spock. What's our orbit status?
- 衰变中，舰长 - 二级异动
- Decaying, captain. - Variance at second level
恶化异常迅速
depreciating unusually fast.
你们断电了，我也对这船知根知底
You're out of power. I know this ship too.
进取号本该是我的
The Enterprise should've been mine.
你从我这里夺走了它
You kept me from it.
本
Ben.
为何要杀害无辜的人？
Why kill innocent people?
无辜？
Innocent?
当官的，绅士们，舰长们，所有人
Officers and gentlemen, captains all.
就是没有芬尼，他很久很久以前的
Except for Finney, and his one mistake
一个错误，他们就是念念不忘
a long time ago, but they don't forget.
我记录了那个错误，本
I logged the mistake, Ben.
怪我吧，不要怪他们
Blame me, not them.
但他们有责任，所有人
But they are to blame. All of them.
我是个好长官
I was a good officer.
我真的是
I really was.
对这项事业，我比任何人都热爱
I loved the service more than any man ever dared.
史波克，我们时间不多了
Mr. Spock, we're running out of time.
先生们，请你们马上到传送室
Gentlemen, if you'll please hurry to the Transporter Room.
史波克先生，法庭还没有得出判决
Mr. Spock, the court has not yet reached a verdict.
我们会听完这个证人的话
We will hear this witness out.
好的，大人
Very well, sir.
还来得及，还可以帮你
It's not too late. You can be helped.
但是如果你杀了那些人
But if you kill all those people
怎么不可以？
Why shouldn't I?
他们杀了我，不是吗？
They killed me, didn't they?
公平交易
It's a fair trade.
詹姆也在这交易里吗？
Is Jame included in that deal?
你说什么？
What do you mean?
她就在舰上
She's onboard by now.
是的，她在舰上
Yes, she's onboard.
你为什么这么做？
Why did you do that?
为什么要把她带到这里？
Why did you bring her here?
筋疲力尽，啜泣不止的芬尼告诉了我
Beaten and sobbing, Finney told me
他破坏首要供能电路的位置
where he had sabotaged
他造成的损害很严重
the prime energy circuits. The damage he had caused
但尚能修补
was considerable, but not irreparable.
若一切顺利，我能在轨道完全衰变之前
With luck, I would be able to effect repairs
完成修复
before our orbit decayed completely.
电力恢复，史波克先生，14点，不断上涨
Power returning, Mr. Spock. Up 14 points and rising.
激活左舷脉冲引擎
Activate port impulse engines.
- 三分之一电力 - 三分之一电力
- One-third power. - One-third power.
异动减少
Variance fading.
轨道稳定
Orbit stabilising.
一切安全，长官
All secure, sir.
除非检察官反对
Unless the prosecution has an objection,
我宣布法庭解散
I rule this court be dismissed.
完全没有意见，大人
Absolutely no objection, sir.
下次再见到你会是什么时候呢？
How long will it be this time before I see you again?
冒着听似神秘主义者似的危险
At the risk of sounding like a mystic
这得看星星的脸色
that depends on the stars.
塞缪尔·科格利让我带给你一份特殊礼物
Sam Cogley asked me to give you something special.
这不是首版藏本什么的，只是本书
It's not a first edition or anything, just a book.
他说这就足够让它独一无二了
Sam says that makes it special though.
我还没机会谢他呢
I didn't have much of a chance to thank him.
他在忙着一个案子
He's busy on a case.
为本·芬尼辩护
He's defending Ben Finney.
他说会胜诉的
He says he'll win.
那我可毫不惊讶
I wouldn't be a bit surprised.
如果一个低级的上尉在一艘星舰的舰桥上亲吻舰长
Do you think it would cause a complete breakdown of discipline
你觉得这会导致纪律涣散吗？
if a lowly lieutenant kissed a starship captain on the bridge of his ship?
试试吧
Let's try.
看，纪律严明，完好如初
See, no change. Discipline goes on.
进取号也一定会的
And so must the Enterprise.
再见，吉姆
Goodbye, Jim.
再见，艾利尔
Goodbye, Areel.
祝你下次好运
Better luck next time.
这次我运气就很好
I had pretty good luck this time.
我败诉了，不是吗？
I lost, didn't l?
她是个好律师
She's a very good lawyer.
当然
Obviously.
确实是
Indeed, she is.
本集结束